あ…
Where's the Lancelot?
ランスロット…
あっ　ゼロ！
Zero!
くっ
It's no use.
I don't remember anything.
駄目だ　何も思い出せない
Where am I?
ここは？
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
夢見てた夢
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
果て無き遠く
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
等身大 音をたてて
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
この手に落ちた
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
頭身台 爪をたてて
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
－遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
ISLAND OF THE GODS
やっぱり 別の島か
Just as I thought.
This is another island.
植生や気温は式根島と変わりはない
そう離れた島ではないな
The vegetation and temperature are no different
than Shikine Island. We can't be that far from it.
インカムも なくしたから
連絡手段がないし
There's no way for me to
contact them without an in-com.
ひとまず水場を確保して ビバークを
できるようにしておいた方がいいか
For now, I'll ensure that I have a source
of water and can bivouac in this area.
あ…
カレン？
Kallen? It can't be.
Excuse me!
まさか…
あの…
ん？
スザク？
Suzaku!
あ！
あ！　その服は黒の騎士団の…
A Black Knight uniform?!
うおお！
本当に君なのか？
It really is you?
ううっ
あ！
うわあ！
ぐ！
ううっ！
んっ…
カレン！
Kallen! Kallen Stadtfeld! You're!
カレン・シュタットフェルト
君は…
Don't call me by that name!
そんな名前で呼ぶな！
私は紅月カレンよ　日本人の！
I'm Kallen Kouzuki, a Japanese!
あ！
じゃあ本当に？
Then, you're really?!
私は黒の騎士団　今さら隠す気はない
I'm a Black Knight!
I'm not hiding it anymore!
では紅月カレン 君を拘束する
Well then, Kallen Kouzuki,
I'm placing you under arrest.
容疑はブリタニアへの反逆罪だ
Your crime is rebellion against Britannia!
チッ
扇達と連絡を取るのは難しいな
It's going to be difficult
contacting Ohgi and the others.
しかし 一般人を装って
ブリタニア軍に助けを求めようにも…
Although I suppose I could
pretend to be an ordinary person...
and ask the Britannian
forces to rescue me, but...
ん？
なるほど
I see. You don't know what happened, either.
君も何があったかは分からない
気づいたら この島に流されていた
When you woke up, you
were on this island. Correct?
そうだね？
ふっ
あんただって遭難してるじゃない
So, you're shipwrecked, too?
Serves you right!
いい気味よ
私の仲間が来れば
捕虜になるのは あんたの方よね
If my people get here,
you're the one who'll be the prisoner!
ゼロが助けに来ると？
You're saying Zero will come to save you?
必ず
Without a doubt!
じゃ その前に教えてもらおうか
Okay, then before he does,
tell me one thing! Who is he really?!
ゼロの正体を
自分で確かめたら？
Why not find out for yourself?
そうか 君も知らないんだね
I see. You don't know, either.
う…
どうして？
How did?!
やっぱりか
I knew it.
ひっかけたの？
You tricked me!
正体を隠しているよりマシさ
That's no worse than hiding my identity.
君は どうしてゼロに従うんだい？
Why do you follow Zero?
さあね　自分で考えたら？
I dunno. Figure that out for yourself!
ルルーシュ
Lelouch.
う！
ルルーシュなのでしょ？
Lelouch, it's you, isn't it?
あ…
誰にも言っていません　本当です
I haven't told anyone, I swear!
だから私を撃つ前に せめて…
So please, before you shoot, at least...
う…
あ…
ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
宇宙探査レーダーチームは
セクションＤからＦへ移動
Underground probe radar team,
move from section D to section F.
サイレントインターバルは…
捜せ！
Find her! Whatever it takes, find Princess Euphemia!
なんとしても
ユーフェミア様を探し出すんだ！
お飾りの副総督なら
らしくしていれば いいものを
Why couldn't she act like the
figurehead sub-viceroy she is?!
このような事
コーネリア様の耳に入ったら…
If Princess Cornelia hears about this!
いやあ～ まっさか浮遊航空艦とはねえ
Oh, my! Who would have
imagined a floating aircraft carrier!
あ…
実用化はデータを取ってから
とか言ってませんでした？
Didn't you say we have to collect
data before practical application?
君らが作る物は皆 興味深いからね
Because I'm very interested in
all of the things you're making.
つい実現したくなるんだよ
I just wanted to see if this could be made real.
ハドロン砲も？
The Hadron Cannon, too?
まず やってみないとね
We had to see if it worked.
一度お会いしたかった
セシル・クルーミーさん
I've been looking forward to meeting
you, Ms. Cécile Croomy. I am...
私は…
シュナイゼル殿下！
Prince Schneizel!
貴様！
You impudent! How dare you look down
upon the second prince of the empire!
第二皇子殿下を見下ろすなど
失礼であろう！
バ… バトレー将軍！
G- General Bartley!
ああ！
あら？
Oh?
いったたた…
お怪我は ありませんか？
You're not injured, I hope.
あ…
シュナイゼル・エル・ブリタニアです
I am Schneizel el Britannia.
Now please, give me your hand.
さあ お手をどうぞ
は… はい
Y... Yes!
も… もったいない
Oh... She doesn't deserve it!
すっかり忠義者ですね　将軍
You're quite a loyal man, aren't you, General?
本来なら 今頃タンブル島の地下深くに
繋がれていたはずの私を
Mainly because he's the one who saved me
from being chained deep under Temple Tower!
救ってくださったのだ
そんなに堅く考えないでくれないか？
I wish you'd stop thinking of me so formally.
今回の件は君のおかげだし
クロヴィスの事もある
You've been of great help in this
current matter, as you were to Clovis.
礼を言うのは私の方だ
It's I who am grateful to you.
わ… 我が君
M- My Lord!
バトレー
Bartley...
では セシル嬢　失礼
Now, my lady Cécile, if you'll excuse me.
で 殿下…
Y-Your Highness!
んじゃ君は基地で待ってて
You can wait for me at the base.
え？　どちらへ？
Huh? Where are you going?
野暮用
A little errand. We're going to
look for Suzaku using the Avalon.
ついでにスザク君も探してくるから
このアヴァロンで
彼 得がたいデヴァイサーだから
昨日みたいな活躍見ちゃうと特にね
It's hard to find devicers like him.
Especially after seeing the
performance he gave yesterday!
あ！　待って下さい
昨日の命令は殿下が？
Wait a moment. Did those orders
yesterday come from the prince?!
控えよ　それ以上は不敬罪にあたる
That's enough! Any further and
you'll be in contempt of royalty!
私です セシルさん　ハドロン砲もね
I did it, Ms. Cécile. And fired
the Hadron Cannon as well.
あの状況でも忘れてはならない事は
優先順位です
Even in a situation like that,
priorities mustn't be forgotten.
そしてイレギュラーが起これば
彼が助かる可能性もあった
Besides, if something unexpected happened,
there was a chance he'd be saved.
そこに賭けたのです
That's what I gambled on.
ユフィの騎士であり
特派の重要なパイロットである
Because he was Suzaku Kururugi, ace
pilot of A.S.E.E.C. and Euphy's knight.
枢木スザクに
あ… はい　分かりました
Yes... I understand.
無礼をお詫び致します
処分は いかようにでも
I apologize for my rudeness.
I stand ready to accept any punishment.
まさか…
部下を守れない私が悪いのです
I wouldn't hear of it! It was my fault
for not protecting my subordinates.
申し訳なかった
I'm sorry.
いつから気づいていた？
When did you figure it out?
ホテルジャックの時
Back during the hotel jacking.
そうか
I see... I said too much without thinking at that time.
あの時は思わず言い過ぎたよ
でも確信したのは今さっき
Still, I wasn't convinced until just now.
ふっ 甘いな 俺も
I'm naive, as well. Still, why didn't
you discuss it with Cornelia?
しかし
なぜコーネリアに相談しなかったんだ？
お姉様は私の言う事なんか…
My sister never listens to me.
それに それ以上に悲しくて
Besides... Things are sad enough as they are.
ナナリー… どうしてる？
How is Nunnally?
一緒に暮らしている
でも 体の方はまだ…
She's living with me,
but she's still crippled.
憎んでいるんでしょうね
You must hate us.
１つだけ教えてくれ
Just tell me one thing.
君は 母が殺された事件について何か…
Do you know anything about the
incident in which my mother was killed?
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
でも お姉様は
いろいろ調べているみたい
But it seems like my sister has been
investigating all sorts of things.
マリアンヌ様はお姉様の憧れだったから
Cornelia really looked up to Lady Marianne.
ん…
私も聞いていいかしら？
May I ask you something now?
ん？
あなたはゼロ？
Are you Zero? Or are you?
それとも…
ルルーシュだよ
I'm Lelouch.
ああ 今ここにいるのは
君の知っているルルーシュだ　ユフィ
Yeah... Here and now, I'm the
Lelouch that you know, Euphy.
ル… ルルーシュ
Lelouch!
あ！
安心したらお腹が すいちゃいました
I think being relieved has made me hungry.
本当に大丈夫？
Are you sure this is all right?
糞や足跡から
ここが野生動物の通り道だと分かる
From the footprints and droppings,
I can tell that wild animals use this path.
くっ
中世からの罠に… くっ
I have a chance to set up... a trap
that dates from medieval times!
アレンジを加えるチャンスだ
はあ…
おっと
Whoops!
へえ うまいもんね
Wow, you're good at that.
君もやってみる？
Wanna try it, too?
食糧確保に協力してくれるなら
拘束を解くよ
I'll let you loose if you help me get food.
あ…
懐柔しようったって
その手には乗らないから
You're not going to win me over like that!
強情だな
Man, you're stubborn!
学校にいる時とは大違いだ
You're not anything like the way you are at school!
ああ…
てこを使っても…
Even using... this as a lever...
私も手伝うから
I'll help you.
な…
皇女殿下に… 肉体労働は…
Manual labor... is not for... royal princesses...
大丈夫
Don't worry.
The system... is perfect.
システムは… 完璧で…
え～っと…
Well, then...
じゃあ果物か何か 探してきますね
Why don't I look for
some fruit or something?
気をつけるんだぞ
Be careful!
はい
Right!
敵戦艦 通過しました
Enemy battleship has passed us.
はあ
ったく
A battleship that can stay still
in midair? Are they kidding?!
空中で止まれる戦艦なんて冗談じゃねえ
やはりこれ以上
この海域に留まるのは危険だ
It's too risky to remain in this
sea sector. Let's pull out.
引き返そう
ああ
Yeah.
いえ あくまでここに留まり
ゼロを捜すべきです
No. At the very least, we should
stay and search for Zero.
確かに
He has a point.
だが捜索隊すら出せない状況
But we can't send out a search party in this situation.
ラクシャータのおかげで
隠れている事はできても
Even though we're able to hide, thanks to Rakshata,
もはやゼロやカレンが
生存している保証すらない
there's no guarantee Zero and Kallen are still alive.
一歩 間違うと組織の存亡に関わる
One misstep and we threaten
our organization's existence.
何を言うのです
What are you saying?!
逆です　ゼロあっての私達
It's the other way round. It's
because of Zero that we're here!
ゼロがいて 初めて組織があるのです
The organization formed
around Zero in the first place!
It's an organization built around its members.
人あってこその組織だ
貴様の物言いは
実にブリタニアらしいな
The way you talk sounds typically Britannian to me!
く…
ではお聞きしたい
All right, then answer me this.
ここには様々な
主義主張の人が集まっています
We have followers of all sorts
of ideologies gathered here.
しかし 曲がりなりにも　それが
まとまっているのは なぜですか？
Yet how is it that they all somehow work together?
結果が出ているからでは？
Because of the results we get?
そして その結果を出しているのは
誰なんですか？
Well then, who is it that gets us those results?!
結果は認めよう
I'll admit he gets results,
but is he worth the lives of everyone?!
しかし… 全員の命と比べられるのか？
時として
１人の命は億の民より重い
There are times the life of a single man is
worth more than a hundred million others.
元軍人なら常識のはずです
I thought that'd be common
sense to a former soldier!
You dare say that here?!
ここで それを言うか
あ あのう…
Um, excuse me...
仕方ない 教えてやろう
Oh, very well. I'll tell you, then. He's alive.
あいつは生きているぞ
願望を聞いている暇は…
We have no time to listen to your wishful thinking...
確定情報だ　私には分かる
It's definite information. I just know.
預言者か お前は？
What, you're an oracle now?
んな事より
ナイトメアの練習しとけって言ったろ？
Didn't I tell you to shut up and train
on a Knightmare, you dumbass?!
このドアホ！
ドアホ？
Dumbass? My, that brings back some memories.
久しぶりだぞ　私に向かって
そんな口の利き方をした奴は
It's been ages since anyone
has dared to call me that.
なんだ？　偉そうに
ゼロの愛人だからって
Oh, like Zero's lover has any right
to act all high and mighty with us!
違うと言っただろ？
下衆な発想しかできん男だ
I said you were wrong,
you obsessively vulgar man!
俺が言いたいのは幹部に向かってだな！
How dare you talk to a leader like that!
Hold on! This whole conversation's out of hand!
ちょっと待ってくれ！
話がそれてる！
ともかくこうしよう
Okay, how about this?
ブリタニアの警戒網の外
安全な海域ぎりぎりで
We hang in a sea sector just outside
of Britannian detection range...
とりあえず 明日いっぱい
待つっていうのは？
and then wait till the end of
tomorrow? That'll be our time limit.
時間制限をつければ
良かろう
Very well.
仕方ありませんね
I suppose we've no choice.
ふん
全く…
For heaven's sake!
お前の いたずらのせいで
つまらん男と会話を…
Thanks to your little prank,
I had to talk to that dull little man.
カレンまであの島に？
You sent Kallen to the island, too?
You have very bad taste for one
who acts like an aloof observer.
趣味が悪いな　観察者を気取って
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
どうしたの？　美味しいのに
What's wrong? They're very tasty!
ん…
明日にはできると思いますよ　落とし穴
I'm sure you're be able to make
your pitfall trap tomorrow.
あ！
ああー 満腹
Ooh, I'm stuffed! I couldn't eat another bite!
食べ過ぎちゃった
今が本当の姿なのかい？
Is this what you're really like?
そうよ　文句ある？
Yeah. Wanna make something of it?
いや
No, I just think it's charming to see you
so much livelier than you are at school.
学校にいるより
よっぽど生き生きして魅力的だよ
あっ…
ふん
ふっ
カレン　騎士団を抜けるんだ
Kallen, leave the Black Knights.
ん！
今ならまだ…
You still have a chance.
捕まったテロリストの末路は悲惨だよ
Captured terrorists don't end up well.
やけにぬるいと思ったら それが本音？
Just when I think you're not so
bad, you show your real intentions.
おあいにくね
あたしはゼロの親衛隊隊長よ
Too bad, but I'm the captain of Zero's royal guard.
ナイトメアで あんたとも戦ったわ
I've fought you in my Knightmare.
あの赤い奴？
That red one?!
そうよ　刺し違えてでも
いつかあんたの白兜を仕留めて見せるわ
Yeah, and while we may
have held each other off,
I'm going to beat that white
helmet of yours some day.
彼のやり方では 未来はないよ
There's no future using his methods.
なら あんたの未来は？
And what about your future?!
支配体制の犬になって
ただ生きてるだけ
Just live on as the conquerors' lapdog?!
名誉ブリタニア人？
第三皇女のナイト様？
An honorary Britannian?
Knight of the third princess?
はっ
Hah!
最後の侍 枢木玄武の名が泣くね！
The name of Genbu Kururugi,
the Last Samurai, weeps!
私は違う
この間違った世界を変えてみせる！
I'm not like you! This world's
wrong and I'm trying to change it!
じゃないと…
If I don't... If I don't, my brother
will never rest in peace!
そうじゃなきゃ…
兄さんが うかばれない
だから私は戦う！
That's why I fight!
勝つ為なら手段は選ばない！
I'll do whatever it takes to win!
ん…
カレン 僕はね…
Kallen, the truth is...
父を殺したんだ
I killed my father.
え？
父は自決したんじゃない
My father didn't commit suicide.
僕が殺したんだ
I killed him.
この手で
With this hand...
星は変わりませんね　あの頃のまま
The stars haven't changed,
have they? From back then.
昔 みんなで見上げた あの星空と
Long ago, we all looked up at the stars together.
あの頃のままでいられたら
どんなに良かったでしょう
How happy I would be if we
could live as we did back then...
戻れないのですか？
Can't we go back?
そうだね
You're right. It would be so good to
just go back to how things were.
戻れたら…
どんなに いいだろうね
ゼロは僕の父と同じだ
Zero is like my father.
世界は自分を中心に
存在していると思っている
He thinks the entire world revolves around him.
だから
多くの人の血が流される事を承知で…
That's why he can allow the blood
of so many people to be spilled...
だから今を受け入れろって？
That's how you can accept how
things are now?! You call that peace?!
そんなのが平和なの？
命よりも大事なものってあるでしょ？
There are things that are more
important than your life, you know!
諦めろと 言うつもりはないよ
I'm not telling you to just give up!
でもね 僕は知っているんだ
But I do know one thing.
間違ったやり方で得た結果が
何を残すか
What do results gained the
wrong way leave you in the end?
行き場のない虚しさと 後悔だけだって
Just regret and an emptiness
that has nowhere to go.
はあ…
じゃあ教えてよ
Then tell me.
お兄ちゃんが生きていた意味って何？
What was the point of my brother's life?
あ！
間違ってるとか 正しいとか
誰が決められるっていうのよ？
Who gets to decide whether
it was "right" or "wrong?"
俺は ユフィ…
俺自身が生きる為にも…
I...
Euphy! Even for me to survive!
I struggle on in shame, still looking
for a reason to go on living.
みっともなく あがいて
生きる意味を探し求める
醜いな　俺は…
I'm such a disgrace.
あ…
枢木君が生きているなら
この神根島に流れ着いているはずだけど
If Kururugi is still alive, he must have
washed up here on Kamine Island.
明朝から捜索隊を出します
We'll send out a search party tomorrow morning.
うん
Hm... And is this what you mentioned?
で これが例の？
はい
Yes. We were excavating it when
the Shinjuku incident occurred.
発掘の途中でシンジュク事変が…
ふうむ
やっぱりクロヴィスは
こういう事に向いていたんだなあ
Just as I thought.
Clovis excelled at this sort of thing.
ねえ その明かりって本当に見たの？
Hey, are you sure you really saw that light?
ああ
Yeah.
捜索隊だろうね
It must be a search party.
確認した上で対応を決めよう
Once we confirm who it is, we'll
decide how to deal with them.
対応…
"Deal" with them?
運搬要員…
思考エレベーターねえ
A Thought Elevator, you say?
考古学は得意じゃないんですが
I'm afraid archeology isn't my strong
point, especially this paranormal stuff!
特に超とか つきそうなのは…
貴様！　無礼であろう！
Why, you... Show some respect!
でもねえ 僕の専門とは違いすぎて
Even so, this is way outside of my field.
こんな事ならセシル君に頼めば良かった
I wish you could have asked
Cécile about this instead.
そんなに嫌がらないでくれよ　父君も
この手の物に ご執心らしくってね
Please don't complain so much.
My father is infatuated with
this as well. Isn't he, Bartley?
そうなんだろ？　バトレー
はい
Yes. We've found identical objects in
a number of places around the world.
同様の物が
世界の数箇所で見つかっており
私が発見した ここを除き
全てが天領とされております
All were placed under imperial
control except for this one.
これは推測ですが
各国に対しての侵攻計画は
This is only a guess,
but we might be invading all these
countries to obtain these objects!
これらのポイントに沿って
行われているものかと
ん～で
And so, to analyze
this occult data,
そんなオカルトのデータ解析に
ガウェインの
ドルイドシステムを使うんですか？
are we going to use
the Gawain's Druid System?
まだ未調整の試作機を…
Untuned prototype that it is.
だから君を呼んだんだよ
Which is why we've called you in.
あはあ
Ah-HAH!
この辺りだと思うんだが
I think it was around here.
ルルーシュ
Lelouch, if it is a search party,
will our time here be over?
捜索隊がいたら
この時間も終わりなの？
仕方ないさ
It can't be helped.
ふっ
こんな頼りない騎士がお供じゃ
食事すらね
I'm such an undependable knight,
I couldn't even get you some food!
うふ
それに
Besides, that's a job for
Suzaku Kururugi, your real knight.
枢木スザク
君の本物の騎士は彼のようだから
あ！
聞いていいかな？
どうして名誉ブリタニア人を？
May I ask? Why did you choose
an honorary Britannian?
それは…
Well...
あ！
う！
なぜ あの２人が？
What are those two doing together?!
スザク！
Suzaku!
え？　ユーフェミア様！
Princess Euphemia!
動くな！　彼女は私の捕虜だ
Don't move! This girl is my prisoner!
ゼロ
Zero!
ここは私に合わせろ
Follow my cue.
あ！
そこにいる私の部下を返してもらおう
I'll take back my subordinate you have there!
We'll exchange prisoners!
人質交換だ
ゼロ　お前はまた！
Zero! Again, you...
近づくな！
Keep back!
ふん　卑怯だというのかね？
Were you going to
call me cowardly again?
ふっふふ
いかなる犠牲を払おうとも
テロリストを排除する
Eliminate terrorists,
no matter what the sacrifice.
君も このルールにこだわり
あるじを見捨ててみるかい？
Are you going to follow that rule
and let your mistress die?
その教示も
もはや破られたというのに
Even though you've already
broken your integrity?
えい！
は！　おやめなさい！
Stop it!
黙ってろ　お人形の皇女が！
１人じゃ何もできないくせに！
Shut up, you little puppet princess!
You can't do anything on your own!
なっ！
Wha?!
構いません スザク！
わたくしの事など気にせず戦いなさい！
I don't care! Suzaku, never mind me! Fight!
皇女殿下！
Your Highness!
今なら！
Now!
うわあ！
この石頭が！
You hardheaded!
何！
あ！
何これ？
Um, what's this?
My Lord, please save yourself!
お お下がり下さい！　我が君！
枢木少佐！　それとまさか…
Maj. Kururugi! And, can it be?
ゼロ！
Zero!
なっ！
バ バカ者！
You fools!
ユーフェミア様もおられる！
Princess Euphemia is with them, too!
Capture them! Capture them!
確保だ！　確保しろ！
チッ
ゼロ！　あそこにナイトメアが！
Zero, that Knightmare there!
よし！　あれを使うか！
Right, we'll use that! Let's go!
行くぞ！
はい！
Yes, sir!
あ…
スザク
Suzaku!
うわあ！
どあっ！
スザク どうしました？
Suzaku, what's wrong?
ありがたい
Thank heaven! Not only unmanned,
but activated, too!
無人の上に起動もしているとは
壁だ！ ユーフェミア様の前に壁を！
Form a wall! Form a wall
in front of Princess Euphemia!
What is this Knightmare?
なんだ このナイトメアは？
はっはは
ツイている
I'm in luck!
あっ…
シュナイゼル！
Schneizel!
彼が… ゼロか…
So, that's Zero...
ああ！　ガウェインが…
Ah! The Gawain!
取り返すのだ！
Get it back! We can't let this
machine fall into Zero's hands!
この機体ゼロごときに渡してはならぬ！
ええいっ
シュナイゼル！
Schneizel, now I'll!
今は…
アナウンスワン アナウンスワン
Alert 1! Alert 1!
Prototype Knightmare Frame Gawain...
出口にサザーランドが！
There are Sutherland at the exit!
Hang on tight!
I'm going through them!
捕まっていろ このまま突っ込む！
ええ？
消え失せろ
Disappear.
うわあ！
チッ　武器は未完成か！
Damn! The weapons are unperfected?!
あ！
ゼロ！　新手が！
Zero! Reinforcements!
心配するな もう１つは作動している
Relax! Another system is operational.
あ！　飛んだ？
We're flying! This Knightmare can fly!
ナイトメアが… 空を！
ふっははは…
ガウェインが… 我々のガウェインが…
The Gawain! Our Gawain!
よい　所詮は実験機
Forget it. In the end,
it was just an experimental model.
それより２人の無事を祝おう
Aside from that,
thank heaven you're both all right.
あ…
シュナイゼルお兄様
Big brother Schneizel!
ユフィ
Euphy, I'm sorry I took so long.
遅くなって すまなかった
そんな事…
Oh, no!
殿下 それでは予定通り
Your Highness, shall we
keep to the schedule?
あ ああ
Hm? Oh, right.
ああ？
枢木スザク少佐
第２級軍規違反の容疑で 逮捕します
Maj. Suzaku Kururugi, you are under arrest for
a grade two violation of military regulations.
え？
お待ちなさい！
Wait, that man is my knight!
You can't do that!
彼は わたくしの騎士！　そのような…
あ…
あとで なんとかしてあげるから
とりあえず今は…
We'll do something about this later.
For now, let them be.
あの… 何が？
Um... Did something happen?
扇と連絡がついた
このまま外洋で合流する
I've contacted Ohgi!
We'll rendezvous with them out at sea.
はい！
Right! Anyway, one other thing...
あ あのそれと…
紅蓮弐式は？
The Guren Mk-II?
回収済みだ
Recovered. You can thank
Asahina and Chiba for that.
朝比奈と千葉に礼を言っておけ
はい！
Yes, sir!
スザク　すまない
Suzaku, forgive me.
お前にだけは
使うつもりは なかったのだが…
I never intended to use
the power on you, but...
あ！
生きろ！
LIVE!
くっ！
枢木少佐 命令を！
Maj. Kururugi, follow your orders!
うるさい！
Shut up! Who cares about them?!
I HAVE TO LIVE!
知った事か そんなもの！
俺は生きなきゃいけないんだ！
どうやって
ランスロットから出たのかは知らんが
I don't know how you
got out of the Lancelot,
ゼロを始末する千載一遇のチャンスを
自分の命を惜しんで ふいにした
but you blew a golden opportunity to
kill Zero in order to save your own life.
抗弁する気はあるかね？
Are you going to protest?
本当に… 自分が？
Was that... really me?
これ以上はない命令違反だ！
This is nothing less
than direct mutiny!
ああ…
枢木が？
Kururugi did that?!
はい
Yes. The details are unknown.
詳細は不明ですが
全く…
イシカワの制圧が終わったと思ったら
Dammit, just when I thought
we'd nailed the lid on Ishikawa...
殿下
Your Highness!
今度はなんだ？
Now what?
キュウシュウブロックの
関門大橋が破壊されました
The Great Kamon bridge in
Kyushu block has been destroyed!
何？
What?!
他 ４箇所で陸路が
They've also destroyed
four other land-routes...
さらに玄界灘に
強襲揚陸艇が多数侵入してきています
with large numbers of assault landing
craft moving into the Genkai sea!
あ！
中華連邦か？　しかし宣戦布告は…
The Chinese Federation?!
But have they made a declaration of war?
いえ それらの艇体には…
No, Highness!
The craft are bearing the flag of Japan!
日本の国旗が！
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
意味もなく繰り返し
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
過去の嘘も過ちも
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
振り返れば
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
シュナイゼルはなぜ あの島にいた？
What was Schneizel doing on that island?
あの場所に
何が隠されているというのか？
Was that area hiding something?
そしてユフィ
And Euphy... While I think I can trust you for a while,
しばらくは信用できるはずだが
カレンとスザクの事もある
there's also what happened with
Kallen and Suzaku to consider...
いや 今はキュウシュウへの対応が先だ
No! First, we have to deal with Kyushu!
それによって黒の騎士団の
That will determine our future.
俺自身の これからが決まるのだから
THE BATTLE FOR KYUSHU
The future of both the Black Knights and myself!